Guide to the Felix S. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Series II, Teaching Career (Boxes 58-61), documents Felix S. Cohen's courses at the Yale Law School (1946-53) and in the Philosophy Department of the City College of New York (1948-53). Since Cohen taught jurisprudence at both institutions, lecture notes which could not be specifically assigned to one or the other have been placed at the beginning of the series. Most of the material is organized by institution and by semester. The files include correspondence with the department about running the course, letters to students, student papers, Cohen's lecture notes, and final exams.
Series III, Writing Projects (Boxes 62-76) contains background material and copies or drafts of Felix S. Cohen's book reviews, articles, and books and pamphlets. In general, the files contain printed copies of the items and or typescript drafts. If the collection does not include a copy of the text, this has been noted in the box and folder list. Lucy M. Kramer Cohen's bibliography of Cohen's writings is published in The Legal Conscience and in the Rutgers Law Review (see Box 91, folder 1469). Background material consists of correspondence leading to publication, notes, published articles on the topic, letters requesting copies, distribution lists, and letters of praise.
"America's Minorities: The Administrative Record" found with other addresses written by Cohen is accompanied by a copy of Secretary of Interior Harold L. Ickes's address "Promise versus Performance" given in November 1944. Cohen's text may be a rough draft of Ickes's speech.
The Books and Pamphlets subseries holds two editions of Cohen's Handbook of Federal Indian Law, the second and the most recent edition. Although no copy of The Legal Conscience, a collection of Cohen's writings edited by Lucy M. Kramer is included, there are several reviews of the work.
Readings in Jurisprudence and Legal Philosophy, first published in 1951, was the culmination of Morris Cohen's and Felix S. Cohen's efforts to provide a syllabus for their courses on philosophy and jurisprudence. Cohen's letters to Emmanuel Rackman (Box 88, folder 1412) reveal that he and his father had privately printed a version of Readings in the 1930s. Cohen revised the work in the late 1940s for use in his own teaching. The collection contains the 1979 revised edition, the syllabus used in Cohen's jurisprudence classes, and a series of untitled drafts. The draft labeled "Source Book" may be the version put together by Felix S. and Morris R. Cohen. The collection also contains correspondence regarding the publication and distribution of the first edition.
The last section of Series III contains works by others which Cohen kept with his writings.
Series IV, Collegial - Institutional Affiliations (Boxes 77-85) consists of files documenting Felix S. Cohen's association with the Institute of Living Law and several private, non-profit action groups and/or professional institutions. The files generally contain publications by and about the institution and information on meetings and membership.
The Institute of Living Law (ILL) was founded in 1940 by Felix S. Cohen, Lucy M. Kramer, Theodore H. Haas, James E. Curry, and Lawrence Koenigsberger. Through publication and contact with government agencies the group hoped "to give expression to liberal and progressive views in the field where law is involved with economics, social science and social policy..." ("Notes on a Projected Institute of Living Law," Box 77, folder 1209). The founding of the ILL is documented in Box 77, folders 1209-12. Some of their publications can be found in Box 77, folders 1213-14. Seven legislative projects (Boxes 77-79) are listed in the box and folder list and each is accompanied by an ILL. These projects often began as a response to legislation, such as Senator James E. Murray's employment bill, the foreign agent registration bill, Senator Guy M. Gillette's propaganda exposure bill. The ILL produced and published an analysis of each bill, sponsored informative radio broadcasts, and communicated with Congress.
Probably the most comprehensive project undertaken by the Institute of Living Law was the issue of propaganda warfare. Concerned with "[t]he propaganda assaults of Nazism, Fascism and Communism" on "the moral and intellectual foundations of our democracy" the ILL published three articles: "Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: The Method of Suppression," "Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: The Method of Exposure," and "Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: The Method of Enlightenment." These articles, largely the work of Felix S. Cohen and Lucy M. Kramer, were separately published in three law reviews in 1942-43. The articles were later collected under the title Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Appraisal. Originally the group had planned a more extensive work entitled "Handbook of Propaganda Warfare." The collection contains a complete draft of this work (Box 80, folders 1250-54) along with a series of preliminary drafts. The ILL gathered extensive background material for the work (Boxes 82-83), including publications by the government and private action groups such as the American Civil Liberties Union and the Council for Democracy.
Series V, Personal Papers (Boxes 86-96) is divided into Correspondence and Family Papers of Felix S. and Lucy K. Cohen, Morris R. Cohen, and Leonora C. and Harry N. Rosenfield, Felix S. Cohen's sister and her husband.
Correspondence (Boxes 86-91) contains letters to and from Cohen dating primarily from the period of his private practice, 1948-53. Most correspondents are family, friends, and colleagues. Communication with Joseph Blau, Huntington Cairns, Elizabeth Carus, The Day, William Hirsch, Mark DeWolfe Howe, Jerome Hyman, Ernest Nagel, Lester M. Nichols, Louis and Jane Roth, Charles Stein, Sidney Wallach, and Philip P. Wiener concerns Morris R. Cohen's writings. Correspondence with Eliot Cohen, Huntington Cairns, Sidney Hook, Samuel Merwin, Jerome Michael, Ernest Nagel, Lester M. Nichols, and Morris Opler focuses on Felix S. Cohen's articles. Sidney Ratner and Roscoe H. Vining ask Cohen to address various groups, while Daniel J. Bronstein, Ruth Calvin, Humbert Cofrances, Harold L. Ickes, Marjorie Merritt, Virginia Mishnun, Richard Powell, and Emanuel Rackman sought Cohen's advice on various legal questions or his help in their careers.
Many friends and colleagues Cohen corresponded with were interested in Indian affairs. People such as Ruth Muskrat Bronson, William A. Brophy, Dennis Chavez (Senator from New Mexico), Henry Cohen, Chester Faris, William Gilbert, Theodore H. Haas, John B. Hart, Harold L. Ickes, Alexander Lesser, Norman Littell, Richard Powell, Sister Providencia, Harry N. Rosenfield, and Howard M. Schott shared their opinions on Indian affairs with Cohen or sought out Cohen for his expertise. Most of the files also contain personal letters and several concern family business.
At the end of the Correspondence section is a series of special files. Cohen's vacation correspondence, letters received while in the Adirondacks, is to and from his secretaries and the staff of Riegelman, Strasser, Schwarz & Spiegelberg (Box 90, folders 1448-50). Cohen maintained a file on charitable contributions (Box 89-90, folders 1438-39) organized alphabetically by organization and a file of invitations (Box 90, folders 1440-44) to attend conferences and to speak, also arranged alphabetically. There is also a file of letters congratulating Cohen on his move from the Department of the Interior to private practice (Box 90, folders 1445-47).
The second part of Series V is material collected by Cohen family members. The files for Felix S. Cohen and Lucy M. Kramer (Box 90-95) have a great deal of biographical information. The files also reflect their socio-political interests. The Morris R. Cohen files (Box 95-96) relate primarily to his written works. The Leonora C. and Harry N. Rosenfield files (Box 96) consist of material about Felix S. Cohen and Morris R. Cohen.
Series VI, Arthur Lazarus Addition (boxes 97-99) represents files Felix S. Cohen created when he worked for the Interior Department which were released by the Interior Department and brought into his private practice. They became the property of the law firm and were donated to Yale in 1991 by Arthur Lazarus who became a partner in the law firm. Most of the files, which date from the 1930s, document the creation of Indian constitutions under the terms of the Indian Reorganization Act. There are a few other files with publications by Labor's Non-Partisan League and concerning Indian issues in the 1940s and 1950s. Box 99, folder 1599 contains an address by Harold L. Ickes on the United States constitution probably written by Cohen.
Oversize contains material from Series I, III, IV, and V. The arrangement, based on the size of the material, parallels the order of the collection.
The papers in Boxes 102-04, folders 1655-92, are restricted until 2025. The dictaphone records in Box 104, folder 1693 are restricted at the curator's discretion. The Restricted Fragile Papers in Box 105, folder 1694-95 may only be seen with the permission of the curator.
Immigrants -- Government policy -- United States; Indians of North America -- Government relations -- 1934-; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Indians of North America -- Alaska; Lawyers -- United States; Billikopf, Jacob, 1883-1950; Bronstein, Daniel J., 1908-; Bronston, Jack Edward; Carus, Elizabeth; Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953; Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 ( Combating totalitarian propaganda: a legal reappraisal); Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 ( Felix S. Cohen's Handbook of federal Indian law); Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 ( Readings in jurisprudence and legal philosophy); Cohen, Henry; Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007; Cohen, Morris Raphael, 1880-1947; Cohen, Victor William; Collier, John, 1884-1968; Curry, James E., 1907-1972; Hart, John B.; Haas, Theodore H.; Holman, Nat; Horn, Frances Lopinsky; Howe, Mark De Wolfe, 1906-1967; Hyman, Jerome; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952; Konvitz, Milton R. (Milton Ridvas), 1908-2003; Lachman, Karl E.; Lesser, Alexander, 1902-1982; Levine, Pearl Ann; Margold, Nathan R., 1899-1947; Mermin, Samuel, 1912-; Merritt, Marjorie; Meyer, Arthur S. (Arthur Simon), 1880-1955; Michael, Jerome, 1890-1953; Mishnun-Hardman, Virginia; Mitchell, Irene Williams; Paul, William, Jr.; Providencia, Sister, -1989; Rosenfield, Harry N. (Harry Nathan), 1911-1995; Rosenfield, Leonora Cohen, 1909-1982; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970; Shientag, Bernard L. (Bernard Lloyd), 1887-1952; Singer, Rita; Steinberg, Isaac Nachman, 1888-1957; Trager, Frank N.; Wallach, Sidney, 1947-1948; Wiener, Philip Paul, 1947-1950; United States. Department of the Interior; United States. Office of Indian Affairs; College of the City of New York (1926-1961); Conference on Jewish Relations (U.S.); Consultative Council of Jewish Organizations; Curry, Cohen & Bingham; Institute of Ethnic Affairs (Washington, D.C.); Institute of Living Law; National Lawyers Guild; New York Association for New Americans; Riegelman, Strasser, Schwartz & Spiegelberg; Yale Law School
- Legal Career, 1931-1953; Series I; 29; (57 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Felix S. Cohen's organization of his files has been largely retained, although some files were moved to fit better the arrangement suggested by the bulk of the material. The original folder titles have been preserved; any alterations or additions appear in brackets []. Subseries headings have been assigned by the archivist to reflect the organization of the material. Although there is a subseries Solicitor's Office Records, Cohen's work for the office is reflected in every subseries. The series is divided into Indian Affairs, Indian Law Survey, Alaska: Natural Resources and Native Affairs, Territories, Solicitor's Office Records, and Private Practice Office Records.
  - INDIAN AFFAIRS
    This subseries documents Cohen's work on Indian issues both at the Interior Department and in private practice.
    - Las Casas, etc. [notes on early Spanish writings regarding Indian land rights], 1940, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Powers of the Commissioner [of Indian Affairs], 1935, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - How Long Will Indian Constitutions Last?, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Constitution - making [correspondence regarding article "How Long Will Indian Constitutions Last?"], 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Invisible [Indian] resources, 1937-41 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Value of land for agriculture vs. recreation; farm tenancy and summer camps], 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anthropology [and administration of Indian affairs], 1934-40, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
    - Law and order in the Indian country [memorandum regarding Wheeler-Howard Act for Justice department], ca. 1934-38 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Decline of dictatorship [over Indians: legal doctrine of Indian self- government], 1934-37 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - The New Trail. I-VII [examination of the Wheeler-Howard Act], ca. 1934-47, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
    - The New Trail [: conferences with tribes regarding the Wheeler-Howard Act], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 17-22)
    - Indians on a New Trail - misc., 1941, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1609
    - Law and order 1904-1935 [regulations on Indian reservations], 1934-35 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Indian citizenship, 1943-45, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25-28)
    - Law and order regulations - draft and report, 1934-35 (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
    - Law and order - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
    - Revision of regulations [for the Indian Service], 1938 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Probate Regulations (revised) [due to Wheeler-Howard Act, re: inheritance], 1935-37 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 5 tribes general - leasing regulations, 1936-38 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Election regulations [reorganized under the Wheeler-Howard Act], 1934-35 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - [Indian] Arts and Crafts Board, 1932-37 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - [Annual report - Revolving Credit Fund], 1944 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - [Indian] credit regulations, 1935-44 (Box 3, Folder 40-43)
    - [Indian] credit regulations, 1945-51, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 44-47)
    - Forest regulations: [timbering on tribal land], 1936 Oct 14 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Law and order: [tribal courts jurisdiction], 1935-38, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Power of Dept. over grazing regulations, 1935-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
    - Revised grazing regulations, 1931-43, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
    - Grazing, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Navajo, Hopi grazing regulations, 1937, 1948, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Hunt v. Pueblo of Acoma, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Glacier Park land program, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 57-59)
    - Indian - routine, 1938-44, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 60-62)
    - Routine, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 63-64)
    - Indian - Routine - 1940, 1940-41 (Box 5, Folder 65-67)
    - Legal Notes and Memos
      - Routine, 1934-37 (Box 5, Folder 68-73)
      - Routine, 1937-38 (Box 6, Folder 74)
      - Tribal organizations - statistical data, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 75)
      - Reports on organization - misc., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 76)
      - Tribal organization - political data, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 77)
      - Solicitor's opinions, 1934-41 (Box 6, Folder 78-84)
      - Legal memoranda, 1934-36, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 85-88)
      - Indian constitutions (Box 6, Folder 89)
      - Constitutional criticism, 1935-36, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Law notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Notes on legal powers of tribe, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Indian - miscellaneous
      - Indian bills, 1934, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - Miscellaneous - Indian, 1934, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - Indian Office Correspondence, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - Enrollment [of Indians], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 96)
      - Indian Service Personnel, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - Letters - Carbons, 1933-34 (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Flathead Power [Plant, Montana], 1936, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Indian Organization
      - Basic Memorandum on Indian Organization, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 100-01)
      - Charters [of various Indian tribes], 1934-36, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 102-03)
      - Model Charter, 1934-37, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 104-05)
      - Model Constitutions, 1935, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 106)
      - Indian Organization Memos, 1936-40 (Box 8, Folder 107-10)
      - Legal Powers of an Indian Tribe Memoranda, 1934, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 111)
      - ["The Powers of an Indian Tribe"], 1934 Oct 25 (Box 8, Folder 112)
      - Oklahoma Organization, 1936-43, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 113-16)
        See also: Oversize, BSD, folder 1602
      - Tribal Organization - General Plans, 1934-37 (Box 8, Folder 117-19)
      - Tribal Organization - General Plans, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 120)
      - Tribal Organization - Legal Data, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 121)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1635
      - Tribal Organization - Anthropological Data, 1933-36, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 122-25)
      - Winnebago Agency, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 126)
        Sent to Lucy M. Kramer in 1982 by Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver, and Kampelman
      - Winnebago Agency, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 127)
      - Tribal Finances, 1937, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 128)
      - I.R.& R. [Indian Relief and Rehabilitation] forms, etc., 1936, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 129-30)
      - Indian Office procedure, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - Non-W.H. [Wheeler - Howard] constitutions, 1935-37, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 132)
      - Resettlement, etc., 1935-41 (Box 9, Folder 133)
      - Resettlement, etc., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 134)
      - Soil Conservation Act, 1937, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 135)
      - Soil Conservation Service, 1935 Nov 25 (Box 10, Folder 136)
      - Indian Civil Rights [address prepared for Margold] (Box 10, Folder 137)
      - Indian [Affairs] Record - 1933-37
        - [Correspondence], 1937-38, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 138)
        - [Drafts of report], 1934-38, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 139)
        - [Background], 1934-37, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 140)
        - [Background], 1932-39, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 141)
      - Inter-American Indian Conference, 1940-53, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 142-48)
      - ["Legislative Material on the Indian Claims Commission Act of 1946"], ca. 1946 (Box 11, Folder 149)
      - [Legislation re: Indian membership rules, Yakima], 1945-46 (Box 11, Folder 150)
        Sent to Lucy M. Kramer in 1982 by Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver & Kampelman
      - [ Indians at Work: A News Sheet for Indians and the Indian Service ], 1936 May 15 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - Mexico [North American Indian policy], 1936-41 (Box 11, Folder 152-53)
        See also: BSD, folder 1603
  - INDIAN LAW SURVEY
    These files document the work of the Indian Law Survey, a joint effort by the Departments of Justice and Interior. This subseries is arranged into Reports and Memoranda and Correspondence, which document the work of unit, "Compilation" and Handbook, the results of the project, and Subject Files, containing background material.
    - Reports
      - Unit's organization, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 154)
      - Personnel, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 155)
      - Job analysis sheets, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 156)
      - Progress reports, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 157)
      - Status reports to Littell and/or Collett, 1939-40 (Box 11, Folder 158)
      - Progress reports on stenographic work, 1939-40 (Box 12, Folder 159)
      - Stenographic reports, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 160)
      - Interpretations of statutes, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 161)
      - Compilation of statutes, 1939, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 162)
      - Reports on statute compilation, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 163-64)
      - Cards [citing statutes] not filed, ca. 1939 (Box 12, Folder 165)
      - Handbook plans of work, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 166)
      - Writing assignments, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 167)
      - Material for Handbook: [inter-department memoranda, reports, pages from compilation], 1939-40, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 168-70)
      - Material for Handbook: [inter-department memoranda, reports, pages from compilation], 1939-40, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 171)
    - Memoranda and Correspondence
      - Administration matters, 1939-40 (Box 12, Folder 172)
      - Collett, Mr. [acting assistant attorney general], 1939 (Box 12, Folder 173)
      - Courts, etc., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 174)
      - Dept. of Interior, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 175)
      - Dept. of Justice, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 176-82)
      - Fabian, Robert H. [chairman of Advisory Committee on Indian Lawbook], 1939 (Box 13, Folder 183)
      - Haas, Theodore H., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 184)
      - Miller, Samuel, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 185)
      - Morris, Mary K., 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 186)
      - Mulroney, Mr. [chief of the Trial Section], 1939 Dec 13 (Box 13, Folder 187)
        See also: Box 13, folders 176-82
      - Pollitt, Mima R., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 188)
      - Renner, Bettie, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 189)
      - Staff, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 190)
      - Stearns, Clifford R., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 191)
    - Compilation
      - "Statutory Compilation of the Indian Law Survey: A Compendium of Federal Laws and Treaties Relating to Indians:", 1940; 46
        - Volume 1 (Box 13.01, Folder 192)
        - Volume 2 (Box 13.02, Folder 193)
        - Volume 3 (Box 13.03, Folder 194)
        - Volume 4 (Box 13.04, Folder 195)
        - Volume 5 (Box 13.05, Folder 196)
        - Volume 6 (Box 13.06, Folder 197)
        - Volume 7 (Box 13.07, Folder 198)
        - Volume 8 (Box 13.08, Folder 199)
        - Volume 9 (Box 13.09, Folder 200)
        - Volume 10 (Box 13.1, Folder 201)
        - Volume 11 (Box 13.11, Folder 202)
        - Volume 12 (Box 13.12, Folder 203)
        - Volume 13 (Box 13.13, Folder 204)
        - Volume 14 (Box 13.14, Folder 205)
        - Volume 15 (Box 13.15, Folder 206)
        - Volume 16 (Box 13.16, Folder 207)
        - Volume 17 (Box 13.17, Folder 208)
        - Volume 18 (Box 13.18, Folder 209)
        - Volume 19 (Box 13.19, Folder 210)
        - Volume 20 (Box 13.2, Folder 211)
        - Volume 21 (Box 13.21, Folder 212)
        - Volume 22 (Box 13.22, Folder 213)
        - Volume 23 (Box 13.23, Folder 214)
        - Volume 24 (Box 13.24, Folder 215)
        - Volume 25 (Box 13.25, Folder 216)
        - Volume 26 (Box 13.26, Folder 217)
        - Volume 27 (Box 13.27, Folder 218)
        - Volume 28 (Box 13.28, Folder 219)
        - Volume 29 (Box 13.29, Folder 220)
        - Volume 30 (Box 13.3, Folder 221)
        - Volume 31 (Box 13.31, Folder 222)
        - Volume 32 (Box 13.32, Folder 223)
        - Volume 33 (Box 13.33, Folder 224)
        - Volume 34 (Box 13.34, Folder 225)
        - Volume 35 (Box 13.35, Folder 226)
        - Volume 36 (Box 13.36, Folder 227)
        - Volume 37 (Box 13.37, Folder 228)
        - Volume 38 (Box 13.38, Folder 229)
        - Volume 39 (Box 13.39, Folder 230)
        - Volume 40 (Box 13.4, Folder 231)
        - Volume 41 (Box 13.41, Folder 232)
        - Volume 42 (Box 13.42, Folder 233)
        - Volume 43 (Box 13.43, Folder 234)
        - Volume 44 (Box 13.44, Folder 235)
        - Volume 45 (Box 13.45, Folder 236)
        - Volume 46 (Box 13.46, Folder 237)
    - Handbook of Federal Indian Law, Drafts, etc.
      See also: Series III. Writing Projects for 1941 and 1982 editions, Box 71-72, folders 1142-43
      - Page proofs, 1940 edition published by Government Printing Office, ca. 1940 (Box 14, Folder 238-39)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folders 1610-14
      - Draft and comments of chp. 9, Individual rights in tribal property; chp. 12, Indian education; chp. 25, Pueblos of New Mexico, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 240-46)